Neeko Blomgren neekode.com

neeko.blomgren@gmail.com (206) 257-8765

https://tinyurl.com/neeko-linkedin

Summary

Front-end developer with an educational background in UX, and experience maintaining Full-Stack. Specializes in TypeScript, React, and other modern tech. Moves quickly to adapt, such as being hired to the Microsoft Teams team and learning AngularJS and Jasmine while working with them. Works fluidly with others of diversified perspectives, skillsets, and perspectives.

Technical Skills

- Languages & Libraries
 - o Proficiencies: React (Hooks), JS/TS, Sass, AngularJS, HTML/CSS, Jasmine, git
 - o Familiar With: GraphQL, SQL, Jest, Java, PHP, C#
- Knowledge OOP, MVC, Human-Centered Design, REST, Web Accessibility, Unit Tests, Asynchronous Code, Agile, DevOps, Responsive Design, Interpersonal Communication

Education

University of Washington Bothell, WA Interactive Media Design, Class of 2018

Work Experience

Web Developer – Microsoft (thru Allyis Inc.)

Nov. 2019 - Present

- I'm currently on the Microsoft Teams Rooms team, and I've been: building out components which have been shipped, resolving bugs, writing unit tests for services, and implementing telemetry, to name some of my responsibilities. I am working during the migration from AngularJS to React, so I work with both. Some of my notable contributions are:
 - Built an AngularJS UI component which allows the user to switch the Calling Screen's (where
 participants are displayed) layout in an MTR room.
 - Built a React UI component which receives event data over the CDL from the AJS codebase through a GraphQL interface to display an indicator on the Calling Screen in the Room.
 - Switched to the Desktop team to help develop and contribute to the Background Effects feature (fixing bugs and implementing telemetry) which you can find on any Teams desktop app.

Jr. Software Engineer (UI) – People Tech Group

Jan. 2019 - Aug. 2019

 Developing solutions for high-priority contracts: built out features, researched then implemented new packages for components, and actively maintained applications. Some of my contributions are:

Neeko Blomgren

neekode.com

- For an app contracted with Costco, I researched, implemented, and tested a notification system across the application's UI which relied on event data traveling thru the React component tree.
- o Implemented a system across the UI which conditionally rendered components based on the currently logged-in user's access permissions (fetched from the database using Redux).

UI Developer Intern – People Tech Group

Oct. 2018 - Nov. 2018

- Lead developer in a front-end team in a corporate work environment simulating real-world projects, in collaboration with UX designers.
- Facilitated and mentored by a front-end professional.
- Was the single intern out of 14 chosen and offered a full-time Junior-level position when the other 13 were offered apprenticeships.

Web Developer - Freelance & Personal

Aug. 2017 – Present

- Developed and designed sophisticated informational website based on a client's requirements for a landscaping company.
- Built, launched, and maintain my personal portfolio built with React Hooks, Sass, and custom components (one of which I'm particularly proud of, ask me about it).